Guide to the Bill Koehnlein Papers TAM.792
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bill Koehnlein Papers
1971-2007
1971-1988
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Koehnlein, Bill
Picher, Marie-Claire
TAM.792
2.5 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
William (Bill) W. Koehnlein was a peace and social justice activist based in New York. Koehnlein was an active member of the anarchist community from the 1960s to the 1980s, involved in numerous organizations. He co-founded the Anarchist Switchboard, a collective project based in East 9th Street in Manhattan. Materials related to that project are included in the collection, as well as booklets, leaflets, independent publications, and typewritten drafts on the topic of anarchism.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Marie-Claire Picher, Bill Koehnlein's wife, in May 2019 with a further accretion donated in August 2021. The accession number associated with these gift are 2019.122 and 2021.033.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
William (Bill) W. Koehnlein (1949-2017) was a peace and social justice activist based in New York. Koehnlein was an active member of the anarchist community from the 1960s to the 1980s, involved in numerous organizations. He co-founded the Anarchist Switchboard, a collective project based in East 9th Street in Manhattan.
Scope and Contents
The Bill Koehnlein Papers primarily consists of materials on the topic of anarchism, including booklets, leaflets, independent publications, and typewritten drafts of original writings. The collection also includes bills, organizational documents, and flyers from 1986 related to Anarchist Switchboard/Alchemical Space, an anarchist space in the East Village.
Appraisal
Three duplicates of pamphlets have been retained.
Anarchism -- United States.; Anarchism -- New York (State) -- New York.; Community activists.; Community organization -- New York (N.Y.); East Village (New York, N.Y.); Picher, Marie-Claire
- Anarchist Publications and Ephemera, 1975-1989; cuid18919 (Box 1)
- Anarchist Ephemera, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
- Anarchist Publications -- Various, 1971-2007 (Box 3, Folder 12-13, Box 4, Folder 1-11, Box 5, Folder 1-8)
- Freedom, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ideas and Action, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- The Match -- Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Match -- Fred Woodworth, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Match -- Issues, 1982-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6-11)
- The Match -- Reprint Series, circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 12, Box 3, Folder 1)
- A Penny for Your Thoughts, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Social Revolutionary Anarchist Federation (SRAF), 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4-7)